-==www.RagBear.com==- 是, 大臣  第2季第3集
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译:颜瑜 校对&时间轴:tpring
死亡名单
抱歉 大臣 报上有些东西您得看看
Minister, there's something in the press you should see.
说我的?      对 可惜登在《侦探》上
About me? I'm afraid it's in Private Eye.
《侦探》?      对 他们专门揭人底牌
Private Eye? Yes... They're exposing something.
不是我为萨冯博士作的品行推荐吧?
Not that character reference I gave for Dr Savundra?
波尔森家那个派对?      我不知道有这回事 大臣
That party at Poulson's? I didn't know about those.
没有 那种垃圾小报就爱编这些
No, that's the thing they make up in that little rag
那是什么?      您最好自己看
What is it? Perhaps you'd better read it.
天哪      太恐怖了 是吗?
Good God Frightful, isn't it?
我能进来吗 大臣?      坐下 汉弗莱 听听这个
May I come in, Minister? Listen to this.
什么?《侦探》啊 太好了
What's that? Oh, Private Eye? Splendid
"加斯里绝密安全报告传奇"
"The saga of the top secret Guthrie Report,
"上周本报报道内容 继续让大臣们头痛"
"revealed to the Eye last week embarrass Ministers.
"据悉某现任内阁大臣 在野时曾饱受电话监听"
"one of the present Cabinet subjected to phone-tapping,
"窃听器以及24小时监视困扰"
"bugging and 24-hour surveillance while in opposition
"他就是政坛大鳄吉姆・哈克"
"was none other than the egregious Jim Hacker."
什么叫"大鳄"?
What's "egregious" mean?
我想是"出类拔萃"的意思
I think it means "outstanding".
哦?
Oh...?
褒义或者贬义
In one way or another.
"他的行政事务部"
"...Jim Hacker, whose department administers
"管理23000名管理人员"
23,000 other administrators.
"风水轮流转 这位大鳄吉姆 如今负责"
Ironically, it is egregious Jim's department now responsible
"提供政府所有电脑化监听设备"
for supplying government's computerised bugging equipment
"可想而知 他正是当今政府监听头目"
Presumably, this makes him the government's chief bugger
太好了
Wonderful
汉弗莱 这是真的吗?      哪部分 大臣?
Is this true? Which, Minister?
我被监听过 现在又负责监听设备
I was under surveillance and am now responsible for bugging
您不会相信那垃圾小报吧?
Surely, you don't believe what you read in that squalid little rag.
别管那个 是真的吗?      别太当真 大臣
Never mind. Is it true? Don't take it too seriously.
我要当真 它说我曾受全面监视
Well, I do This says I was under total surveillance.
我是国会议员 自由公民 这直接践踏民主核心
An MP and free citizen It cuts at the very heart of democracy
还违反欧洲人权公约 知道吗?
It contravenes human rights.
噢 对...
Oh, yes...
监视是打击有组织犯罪的必备武器
Surveillance is indispensable against organised crime.
你不是把政客归为有组织犯罪吧?
You're not describing politicians as organised crime?
也打击无组织犯罪 当然
Disorganised crime, too, of course
汉弗莱 我在《改革》做编辑时专门为此写过社论
Humphrey I once wrote a leader on this as editor of Reform
并发起过全国请愿 抗议官僚们多管闲事
and started a petition against bureaucratic busybodies,
到处监视人们 窃听电话
bugging and phone-tapping.
如今我从《侦探》而不是你汉弗莱那里得知
Now I learn from Private Eye, Humphrey, not from you,
我负责所有监听设备 你怎么没告诉我?
that I'm responsible for it, and you never told me.
您没有问啊
You didn't ask.
幸好我们有自由的报纸 有仗义执言的文章
Thank God for a free press and for one fearless journal
您刚叫它垃圾小报
You said it was a squalid rag.
伯纳 你的政治觉悟有待提高
Sharpen up your antennae.
要学会用发展的眼光看问题
Learn to adapt more flexibly to a developing situation.
我明白了 对不起
I see. I'm sorry.
监视记录都送到哪里?
Where are the transcripts of these bugged conversations?
它们会被写成报告
They were put into a report.
给谁看过?      一直交给内政大臣
Who got these reports? The Home Secretary gets them.
一直? 一直?
Gets them? Gets them?
不是写您的 大臣 现在不是了
Not about you, Minister. Not now.
现在只给他反对党的报告
Now he'll be getting reports about Her Majesty's opposition.
谁把这些拿给他?      军情五处吧 我猜
Who gives them to him? Ml5, presumably.
你似乎对这一切很冷静啊      是的 大臣
You seem very calm about all this. Yes, Minister.
这太恐怖了 一名卓著的公民
I think it's horrifying, a distinguished citizen -
可以说 一名出类拔萃的英国公民      是哦
if I may say so, an extremely distinguished British citizen -
为祖国鞠躬尽瘁一辈子
who's given his life's service to his country,
发现官僚们暗地里听着他的每一句话
finds these bureaucrats have listened to his every word.
他的电话 他吼老婆骂孩子
All his phone calls. His rows with his wife and daughter.
他私下约见会计... 不是说我
His private arrangements with his accountant Not that I..
不 绝对不是      为什么 汉弗莱?
No, quite so. Well, why, Humphrey?
为什么监视 还是为什么监视您?     两个都要问
Why surveillance or why you? Both
反正答案是一样的      那干吗分成两个问题?
It's the same answer. Why split it into two questions?
我不想冒险回答您没问的问题 大臣
I didn't want to risk answering a question you weren't asking.
那我现在问你了 为什么监视我?
I'm asking you now. Why was I under surveillance?
再明显不过了 介意我坐下吗?
It's perfectly obvious. Do you mind?
您看 大选前有传闻
Before the election, it was rumoured
说您会任国防部长
you'd be appointed Defence Secretary.
所以呢?
So?
首相要交给您国防部 为国家利益着想
If the PM was giving you defence, in the national interest,
军情五处得先确定您不是安全隐患
that Ml5 must be satisfied you weren't a security risk.
侵犯我的隐私权      总比侵犯您的国家好 大臣
My privacy was invaded Better than your country, Minister.
你被监视过吗?
Have you ever been under surveillance?
我吗 大臣?      是你
Me, Minister? You.
我是个公务员
I'm a civil servant
伯尼斯和麦克林也是(冷战时期克格勃间谍)
So were Burgess and MacLean.
那是...      还有菲尔比(同上)
Oh, well... And Philby
他们不是常任秘书
They weren't Permanent Secretaries.
做常任秘书的人
One becomes a Permanent Secretary
必须一贯忠诚可靠
after a life of reliability and integrity
经过最严格细致的筛选
The rigorous selection procedures winnow out all
只留下最正直可敬的公务员
but the most upright and honourable public servants.
那大臣呢?      大臣当然有许多杰出品质
And what about Ministers? They have many dazzling qualities
比如...
Including...?
高度的思想服从以及精神可操纵性
Enviable intellectual suppleness and moral manoeuvrability.
你要说什么 汉弗莱?
What are you trying to say?
他们不可信 当然不是您 大臣
You can't trust them Not you, of course, Minister.
不像公务员 大臣是随机抽取而来
Ministers, unlike civil servants, are selected at random
全凭首相一时兴致
by prime ministerial whim,
报答他们莫须有的贡献
in recognition of dubious services rendered,
或者为避免任命真正的贤才
or to avoid appointing someone of real ability.
不是说您 大臣 您当然值得信赖
Not you, Minister You certainly are to be trusted.
这么说吧 您几乎可以当公务员了
You might almost be a civil servant yourself
是夸我吗?      是的 大臣 最高的赞赏
Is that a compliment? Indeed. The ultimate compliment.
大臣 您相信您的所有内阁同僚
Would you trust every Cabinet colleague
都不会泄密吗?
never to betray a confidence?
反对党领袖呢?      他们? 开什么玩笑
And all the opposition front bench? You must be joking
您当时也是反对党
You were in the opposition at the time.
随便吧 汉弗莱 我还是要阻止这种事
Be that as it may, I have decided I'm going to stop it.
但这归内政部管 大臣      至少要加大难度
This is a Home Office matter.  I'll make it harder.
既然我负责设备 我要设置些民主保障
If I'm responsible for bugging, I want democratic safeguards
您是不是建议 人们不受监视
Are you suggest that people won't be put under surveillance
除非他们填一份同意表呢?
until they've signed a form agreeing to it?
不 要由两院设置特别委员会 上院法官核准
No, we'll have a select committee to vet every application,
每延长2周 需重新申请
no surveillance to last over two weeks without application
你能着手帮我处理吗 汉弗莱?
Will you set the wheels in motion, please, Humphrey?
好的 大臣
Very well, Minister.
伯纳 给每位内阁成员送一份摘要
Bernard, send a minute to each Cabinet member.
我要找个后座议员质询内政部长
I'll plant a question for a backbencher to ask.
"您能向下院保证 各位同僚没有受监视吗?"
Can you assure us no colleagues have been under surveillance?
这就差不多了吧?      当然 大臣
That should shake him. It certainly will.
让《快报》的沃尔特福勒今晚到下院找我喝一杯
Ask Walter Fowler of the Express to meet me for a drink.
为什么呢 大臣?      政坛泄密第一法则
What for, Minister? First law of political indiscretion:
酒后吐真言
Always have a drink before you leak.
能写成报导吗?      能
Will it make a story? Yes.
"大臣为反电话窃听而战" 行
"Minister fights for phone-tap safeguard." Yes
会放在哪里?      国内新闻头条
Where will they run it? High up on the home news page.
不是头版吗?      能署明是你吗?
Not on page one? Can I attribute it?
"大臣透露"?      不行不行
"Minister speaks out"? No, no, no.
那源头怎么说呢? 也不能说 "官方公布"
Where did I get the story? I can't say Officially announced
"政府发言人"?
"Government spokesman"?
"大臣亲信" 怎么样?
How about, "Sources close to Minister"?
不行 别让大家知道是我透露的
Hold on, I don't want everybody to know I told you
不能说"议会呼声日渐高涨"吗?
Couldn't you do, "Speculation is growing in Westminster"?
欠点力度
A bit weak.
"非官方发言人"?
"Unofficial spokesman"?
本周已经用过两次了
Used that twice this week already
内阁漏得跟筛子一样 是吧?
The Cabinet's leaking like a sieve, isn't it?
不能写是筛子...不 内阁领导人吗?
Attribute it to a leading member of the sieve... Cabinet?
不行
No...
管你叫"消息灵通人士"怎样?
How would you like to be "an informed source"?
好 "消息灵通人士"
OK. "Informed source."
真好笑 对吧 说某人"消息灵通"
Quite a joke, isn't it, describing someone as "informed"
而他的常任秘书却是汉弗莱・阿普比爵士
when his Permanent Secretary is Sir Humphrey Appleby?
我们的电话 私人对话 都被录了音转成文本
Everything we said on the phone, recorded and transcribed.
真丢人      是有点丢人
It's humiliating It is a little humiliating.
军情五处有人知道 你在家也说外头那套话
That Ml5 know you talk at home as you talk in public.
国民生产总值 贷款条件 党内议程草案
Gross product, borrowing requirements, draft agendas...
不是这些 是说我们私底下的聊天
I didn't mean that I meant our private talk.
我怎么就没想到 "你带车钥匙了吗?"
I hadn't thought of that..."Got the car keys?"
"没 我以为你带了" 真能让政府垮台
"I thought you had them" That'll bring the government down
你没把它当真      干吗这么想?
You're not taking it seriously. What gives you that idea?
他们能听到我们...在床上说的
They might've heard what we said... in bed
怎么 你打呼噜用密码吗?
Why? Do you snore in code?
你在暗示什么吗?      既然你问了 快放假了
You trying to tell me something? Since you ask,
要不要出去度周末 像以前那样?
why don't we go away for the weekend like we used to?
好啊 怎么不要? 管他的
Yes. Why not? What the hell
去金伯利草原吧      好 在哪?
Let's go to Kingsbury Down. Where?
就是我们度蜜月的地方 亲爱的
Only where we spent our honeymoon, darling
啊 对
Yes...
你在那里第一次向我解释
Where you first explained to me
流通速度对货币供应净增值的影响
Velocity of circulation on the net growth of money supply.
对 我想起来了
Yeah... I remember.
都听见啦 小伙子们?
Did you get that, boys?
大臣...上了死亡名单?
The Minister... on a death list?
什么是国际自由军?
Well, who are the International Freedom Army?
我们还没查出来      为什么要暗杀大臣?
We do not, as yet, know. Why assassinate the Minister?
他又没有威胁性
He's so harmless
那也不能拿大臣的性命去冒险
Nevertheless, we cannot risk the Minister's life.
当然不能 就是说全面...?      对
No. That means the full...? Quite
早安 大臣      早安 大臣 您好吗
Morning, Minister Morning, Minister, how are you?
对不起迟到了 昨晚没睡好     那太遗憾了 大臣
Sorry I'm late. Didn't sleep well. Sorry to hear that.
真的 我觉得像要死了
Actually, I feel like death.
可能这样也好
Perhaps that's just as well.
看今早的《快报》了吗?      看了
See this morning's Express? Indeed.
"大臣限制电话监听"     真不知他们哪来的消息
Minister acts to curb phone taps Wonder where they got that
大概有人泄密 真恐怖对吧?
A leak, I suppose. Terrible, isn't it?
真恐怖
Terrible.
这只会激励我干到底
It only reaffirms my determination to act.
大臣 您真的已经三思了吗?
Are you sure you've considered all the implications?
对 自由公民享有隐私权
Yes. Free citizens have a right to privacy.
要是军情五处有理由相信 这些自由公民
But suppose Ml5 believe these free citizens were,
容我假设一下
to take a purely hypothetical example,
计划暗杀一位大臣呢?
planning to assassinate a Minister?
英国人民的自由远重于大臣的生命
Freedom of the people is worth more than a Minister's life
自由是无价之宝
Freedom is indivisible.
大臣牺牲无所谓
Ministers are expendable.
公众人物得随时准备成为暴徒的目标
Men in public life expect to be the target of fanatics.
大臣理应把生死置之度外
It is a Minister's duty to set his life at naught.
他得站出来高呼 "我在这里 向我开炮"
Able to stand up and say, "Here I am Do your worst"
而不是战战兢兢
And not cower in craven terror
藏身于电子监视设备
behind electronic equipment,
秘密话筒
secret microphones
和极权国家种种骇人手段后面
and all the hideous apparatus... of the police state.
汉弗莱 你不用说了
Ahem... I don't want to hear about it.
大臣 关于此事我还得说一句话
I must say one more thing on this matter.
好吧 就一句 简单点
Very well. Be brief.
特工处发现您上了死亡名单
Special Branch have found your name on a death list.
这事毫无参考价值
That has no bearing on the situation.
什么?
What?
特工处发现您上了死亡名单
Special Branch have found your name on a death list.
什么死亡名单?      就是暗杀名单
A death list...? An assassination.
我知道什么叫死亡名单 但你什么意思?
I know what you mean by death list, but what do you mean?
我还真没法解释了 大臣
I don't think I can put it any more clearly, Minister.
坦率地说
To put it absolutely bluntly,
秘密调查证明有这样一份文件
investigations have proved the existence of documents
它的出处无从考究
whose provenance is unestablished
但它会造成一次补缺选举
but whose effect would be to precipitate a bye-election.
你是什么意思?
What do you mean?
您上了死亡名单 大臣
You're on a death list, Minister.
谁列的? 为什么?
Who and why?
叫国际自由军 一支新生的城市游击队
The International Freedom Army, a new urban guerrilla group.
干吗跟我过不去?      您可能记得
What've they got against me? As you may recall,
有谣言说内阁要重组
there have been rumours of a Cabinet reshuffle,
据称您可能出任国防部长
and your name was linked with the Ministry of Defence.
他们是谁?      说不好 可能是爱尔兰分裂派
Who can they be? An Irish splinter group?
赤军旅 巴解组织 黑色九月 或者国产暴徒
Baader-Meinhof PLO or Black September or home-grown loonies
无政府主义者 激进左翼 利比亚人
Anarchists, Maoists, Libyans,
伊朗人 意大利红色旅 都有可能
Iranians or the Italian Red Brigade, for all we know.
他们互相勾结 所以也可能是一群新兴的自由杀手
All connected. it could be a group of freelance killers
特工处也无从下手
Special Branch don't know where to start.
你说名单 上面不会只有我吧?      不是 大臣
The list isn't just me? Not just you, Minister.
一定有几百人...      只有三个
There must be hundreds on... Just three.
只有三个
Just three.
喂? 好的 特工处的福雷队长来了
Yes? Commander Forest of Special Branch.
请他进来?      好的
Shall I...? Please do.
特工处要内政大臣派探员保护您
The Home Secretary wants detectives to protect you.
他会通知您的      探员?
This man will inform you. Detectives?
他们防不住放黑枪的 对吧? 没人能
They can't protect you against the assassin's bullet
当然不 但他们能将犯人绳之以法
But they can determine the assassin is brought to trial.
当然 是在受害被撂倒之后
After the victim has been gunned down, of course.
特工处的福雷队长
Commander Forest of Special Branch.
早安 队长      早安 先生
Morning, Commander. Morning, sir.
请坐      谢谢 先生
Sit down. Thank you.
您听说那个名单了吧 先生?
You've been told about this list, sir?
什么名单? 噢 名单 对
List? What list? Oh, list, yes.
我简单讲一下标准防范措施
I'll brief you on the standard hazards and precautions.
谢谢 伯纳      我不用太当真吧?
Thank you, Bernard. Do I have to take it seriously?
这个随您便 先生 我们建议...
In a sense, that's up to you. We advise...
换别人早就惊慌失措了 但对我只是日常工作
Most people in a frightful funk, but it's all in work
勇气可嘉 先生      谢谢
I admire your courage, sir. Thank you.
那好
Right, well...
放马过来 我是说...
Shoot. I mean...
暗杀事件分为四种
Assassination hazards fall into four categories:
枪杀 炸弹 毒药 还有所谓的意外
Bullets, bombs, poisons and so-called accidents.
当然还有煤气 勒死 捅死 溺死
There's also gassing, throttling, stabbing, drowning,
绞死 宗教活祭 但在英国不常见
garrotting and ritual disembowelling are uncommon in the UK.
那就好      先从枪杀开始
All right, then. Start with bullets.
暗杀者从高楼或车里开枪
There's your assassin on a tall building or in a car,
也可能藏在人群中然后 砰
your killer in a crowd and phut
还有上门的不速之客 货车里的神射手
There's the unexpected house caller your marksman in a van,
伸进车窗的左轮手枪 所以
and the revolver through your car window.
远离人群 远离窗口
So avoid crowds and keep away from windows.
队长 可以为办公室装防弹窗帘吗?
could I suggest bullet-proof curtains for the office?
还防弹...      中午就装 先生
Bullet-proof By lunchtime, sir.
您的伦敦住宅也装 等我们彻底改造之后
We'll fit them in your London flat when we do the place over.
彻底改造?      常规的锁 警报器
Do it over? The usual locks, security alarms.
当地警察24小时巡逻 电话监听
24-hour patrols by local staff, phone taps.
这是常规?
Just the usual?
还有几名全天候贴身保镖
You'll have bodyguards round the clock.
不要亲自开门 叫司机关好车窗
Never answer your door in person, keep car windows locked.
等红灯不要停靠人行道
Never draw up by the pavement at lights.
您不想恐怖分子跳进来绑架您吧
You don't want a terrorist to jump in
不要      当然不想
No. Course not
如果他开车堵您的车 从侧面别过去
If he draws his car in front of yours, sweep it aside,
炸弹 有汽车炸弹 还有信 别拆邮件
Bombs Car bombs you know, but never open letters.
目前您的信由我们代收
For the time being, we'll re-direct them.
毒药 当心别人送的食物 饮料 糖果 巧克力
Now, poisons... Be suspicious of gifts of food, chocolates.
每天早晨检查牛奶瓶盖 防止有针孔
Check the milk bottle every morning for hypodermic holes
不要忘记戳进小腿的注毒雨伞
Don't forget the poisoned umbrella jabbed into the calf.
再说意外
Now... accidents.
不要在人行道旁 河岸 铁路月台边走
Never walk along pavements, rivers, railway platforms.
可别太便宜他们 先生
We don't want to make it too easy for them.
特别是电气铁路 所以不要坐地铁
Especially the electric railway so avoid the Tube.
触电也是常见手法
Electrocution... another favourite.
稍稍改造一下电视 电锅 面包机
A little tinkering with the telly, toaster
收音机 电热毯 完事了
electric blanket and Bob's your uncle
也就是玩完了
Your late uncle.
这些都要常检查 有问题吗?
They have to be checked. Any questions?
好 给您常规预防措施表
Good Here's your list of standard safety precautions.
保持联系      谢谢 队长
I'll be in touch. Thank you, Commander.
如果您被推出窗外 下面有栏杆
If you're pushed out of a window with railings underneath,
尽量大头朝下
try and land on your head.
痛快
Quicker
汉弗莱 怎么在恐怖分子找到我前找到他们呢?
how do we find these terrorists before they find me?
窃听电话和电子监控嫌疑人是最好的方法
Phone tapping and surveillance of suspects is the best way,
但这会严重侵犯到个人隐私
but it does incur intrusion on individual privacy.
话说回来
On the other hand...
人民代表旨在...代表人民
the people's representatives must represent the people.
威胁他们就是威胁民主 对吧?
Any threat to them is a threat against democracy, isn't it?
会吗?
How?
这些威胁会侵犯
These threats constitute
人民的天赋权利
an attack on the people's inalienable democratic right
领导是他们选的
to have leaders of their choice
得不惜一切代价严密保护
who must be protected by every possible means
不管我们对这种状况多么遗憾
no matter how much we regret the necessity for doing so.
说得好 大臣 正是我的想法
Beautifully argued, Minister. My view exactly.
不然您就要完蛋了
Or else you're a dead duck.
天哪 这是什么?
Good God What's that?
大臣 请愿书到了      请愿书?
The petition's arrived. Petition?
反对电话窃听与监视的请愿书
Against phone tapping and surveillance.
您在野时发动的 225万个签名 大获成功
The one you started in opposition. 2.25 million signatures.
但我们需要监视啊
But we need surveillance
这是打击有组织犯罪的必备武器 对吧?
It's an essential weapon in our fight against crime, right?
精辟 我就说不出来
I couldn't have put it better myself.
明白了 要把它们存档吗?
I see. Shall I file it?
存档? 销毁了 别让人找到
Shred it No one must find it.
既然这样 还是存档最好
In that case, I think it's best I file it.
真是再度蜜月的好方法啊
Great way to spend a second honeymoon
几人的桌子?
Table for...?
8人      2人
Eight Two.
窗边有个好位子
I've a nice table by the window.
我们选定了目标的桌子      目标?
We've chosen the target's table. Target?
对不起 大臣 厨房门旁边那张
Sorry, Minister. Over there by the kitchen door.
您坐这里 先生
You sit here, sir.
罗斯警官看守厨房门 您的逃生路线
Ross will be watching the kitchen door, your escape route.
员工里不会有刺客 我们早上才订的位子
Not expecting assassins here since we only bookedmorning.
我坐窗边 要是听到枪响 钻桌底就行
If you hear gunshots, get under the table.
我其实不怎么担心
I'm not really worried.
只是开香槟 亲爱的
It was just a champagne cork, darling.
我演习一下
Just practising.
我要一份意大利腊肠面
I'll have spaghetti bolognaise,
T骨牛排 豌豆 青豆 花椰菜 薯片
then T-bone steak, peas, beans, cauliflower and chips,
一瓶1961年份罗特希德男爵葡萄酒
and a bottle of Chteau Baron Philippe de Rothschild 1961.
这份工作很累人
Takes it out of you, this job.
很漂亮 对吧      很漂亮
Beautiful, isn't it? Beautiful.
安静平和
Quiet and peaceful.
离开一切喧嚣真是太好了
Lovely to get away from it all.
太好了
Lovely.
还可以吧?      很好
This all right for you? Lovely.
我不想看007 说好了看《白日美人》的
Not James Bond? I thought it was "Belle du Jour".
对 可他们不想看外国电影
Yes, but they didn't want to see a foreign film.
我看够了
I can't stand this.
目标在里面了吗?      对 目标夫妻都在
Target in there now? Yeah, with his wife.
还出去吗?      不了 他们睡下了
They going out again? Nah, turned in for the night.
他们好像不怎么开心啊
They don't seem to be enjoying the holiday.
为什么呢?
Wonder why...?
我在这睡不着
I can't sleep here.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
这是干什么?
What the hell's all this?
本地警方 先生 他们要表示配合
Local force, sir, showing they're doing their bit.
进来 噢 你进来了
Come in. Oh, you're in
抱歉 先生 可以检查一下窗户吗?      请吧
May I just check the windows? Go ahead.
谢谢 晚安 先生
Thank you. Goodnight, sir.
睡个好觉
Sleep well.
别担心 亲爱的 你会习惯做名人的妻子的
Don't worry. You'll get used to being a famous man's wife.
那就好了
I hope so.
我可不想做名人的寡妇
I don't want to be a famous man's widow
可我不明白
But... I don't follow.
你说要阻止监视监听
You want to stop phone tapping,
请愿书得到了225万个签名 足以大书特书
you get this petition of 2.25 million signatures
但你却不愿发表一句感谢的话
and you won't even give me a quote saying you welcome it.
说"保证实施其纲领"如何?
A promise to implement its recommendations?
没那么简单 沃尔特      怎么?
It's not that simple. Why not?
有安全隐患     隐患随时都有
There are security implications. There always were.
好 这个新闻更劲爆 "大臣否决自己的请愿"
I'll make a bigger story: Minister rejects his own petition
等一下 我...
Now, hold on I...
到底同意还是否决?
Are you accepting it or rejecting it?
不
No.
编辑要我问 是不是上死亡名单
My editor asks if being on this death list
改变了你对电话监听的立场
has altered your views on phone tapping.
天啊 真是异想天开
Heavens What an extraordinary idea
那为什么要改变论调呢?      没有改变论调
So why this change of tune? No change of tune.
汉弗莱爵士能说句话吗?      汉弗莱 什么事?
Can Sir Humphrey see you? Humphrey What can I do for you?
能出去一下吗      抱歉 马上就好
Excuse us. Won't be a minute.
我出去等      多谢配合
I'll wait out there.
周末还好吗 大臣?
Good weekend?
太好了 我 安妮 还有特工处一半人
Marvellous. Me, Annie and half of Special Branch.
警察们武装到牙齿 太难忘了      职责所系啊
Rozzers with guns. Unforgettable The burdens of office
不能老这样下去      说得好 大臣 不会继续了
This can't go on. You said it It isn't going to.
特工处刚通知 将撤回对您的保护
Special Branch is withdrawing your protection.
等一下 我不是那个意思 为什么?
Wait a minute I didn't mean... Why?
警察部门人员编制不足
They've suffered an acute personnel establishment shortfall.
他们干嘛?      人手短缺 不保护您了
They're what? Short-staffed. No more protection.
人手短缺?
Short-staffed?
苏联总理明天访问首相别墅 他更危险
There's a threat to the Soviet premier at Chequers.
但他是俄国人 我是英国人      实际上
But he's Russian, I'm British In fact,
特工处相信您已经没有生命危险了
They believe the threat to your life has diminished.
他们怎么知道?
How do they know?
监听到一段对话
Surveillance of a conversation.
说的什么?      没什么...
What did it say? It's of no...
好了汉弗莱 我有权利知道
I've a right to know.
这段对话是说
Well, it was to the effect that,
考虑到您的职责定位暧昧不明
in view of the nebulous and inexplicit nature of your remit,
您在中心政治决策过程中 据信通常施加
arguably peripheral nature of your influence on decisions
边缘化和外围的影响
within the political process,
他们重新调整了行动优先性
there could be a case for restructuring their action priorities
将您从近期议程中剔除了
so as to eliminate your liquidation from their agenda.
他们这样说吗?
They said that?
这是中心思想
That was the gist of it.
什么意思? 说人话
What's it mean in English?
就是说 他们觉得您不够重要
It means that they don't think you're important enough
不值得暗杀
for it to be worth assassinating you.
哦
Oh
当然 我不同意      你是说...
I don't agree, of course. You mean...?
什么?
What?
他们应该暗杀我?      不 不 不
They should assassinate me? No, no, no
你也觉得我不重要?      不 不
I'm not important enough? No, no...
我是说 您很重要
I mean you are important enough,
但还是不杀为好
but they shouldn't assassinate you anyway.
太好了 反正我也没担心过      当然 大臣
That's marvellous. Not that I was ever worried.
福勒先生问还要多久
Mr Fowler's waiting.
对 请他进来
Yes, bring him in.
伯纳 请愿书还在吗? 在就给福勒先生看看
Have we still got that petition? If so, show Mr Fowler.
请愿书? 但您说...
The petition? But you said...
对 我说过 伯纳 还是拿进来吧
Yes, I did, but bring it in.
发展的眼光 伯纳      对对 没错
Antennae, Bernard. Yes Yes, indeed.
您是要把请愿书...      对了 伯纳
The petition you were pleased...? That's right.
天哪
God
吉姆 你得在报上表态      当然
The paper must have an answer.  Of course.
就这么说 我热烈欢迎这些请愿书
I want you to know I welcome this petition warmly
它可不能掩盖起来
It's not the sort of thing you can sweep under the carpet
至于死亡名单 大臣牺牲无所谓
As for death lists, well, Ministers are dispensable,
自由是无价之宝 对吧 汉弗莱?
but freedom is indivisible, right, Humphrey?
是 大臣
Yes, Minister.
破烂熊字幕组 -==www.RagBear.com==- 欢迎加入